cclonline.com 2018-09-06

# Privacy Policy - Policies | CCL Computers

## 1.0 About us

CCL is a company incorporated in England with company number 3224671. Our address is CCL Computers, Inmoor Road, Cross Lane, Bradford, BD11 2PS

## 2.0 Information Collected

Any personal information we collect from this website will be used in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998, the General Data Protection Regulations, and other applicable laws. Information supplied by customers will be used solely for the use of provision and improvement of product and services supplied by CCL Computers Ltd. The details that we collect will be used for the following purposes:

2.1 When opening an account and placing an order with us we require contact information (such as details of your name, delivery address, invoice address, e-mail address), financial information (such as credit or debit card number, the card’s CSV number and expiry date) and unique identifiers (such as username and password). Contact information and details of your order will be kept on our server in case there are any issues with the product. We may need to contact you in relation to your order and may contact you by email, phone or SMS to tell you about delivery or any issues with your order.

2.2 We do not store full credit card information on our servers but we do store a payment token, the expiry date and the last four digits which will allow us to accept future payments without the need for you to enter full card details.

2.3 We automatically receive and record information from your browser or your mobile device when you visit the Site, such as your IP address or unique device identifier, cookies and data about which pages you visit in order to allow us to operate and provide the Services. This information is stored in our database, in log files and is collected automatically. We may combine this information from your browser or your mobile device with other information that we collect about you. This information is used to prevent fraud, to analyse and understand how our website works for visitors.

2.4 We may also automatically collect device-specific information when you use our Services. This information may include information such as the hardware model, operating system information, browser information, IP address, and device identifiers.

2.5 We collect information about your use of the website for analytics, including your IP address and browser information

2.6 We also request for a telephone number which enables us to contact you in the event of there being a problem or query with your order or account. 

2.7 Should you enter a competition or other promotional feature on our website we may ask you for your name, address, e-mail address and telephone number in order that we may efficiently administer the competition and promotion as well as notifying the winners.

2.8 Calls to the Contact Centre maybe monitored or recorded for quality control and training purposes and if you visit our shop CCTV is in operation for security and theft prevention. 

## 3.0 How we use this information

The details we collect will be used to provide the best possible service for customers using our site. We may need to pass on your information to specific third parties in order to do so. These are:

3.1 If you consent, your order details to our authorised repairer Mendit and to the manufacturer of any device you have bought in order to repair under warranty.

3.2 We will provide your first name, surname, invoice address, delivery address, company name, email address, telephone numbers and IP address along with your payment details, such as your credit card number, expiry date, CVC number, cardholder name (and any other payment information that you enter on the Site) to our payment provider. This information is used for the purpose of fulfilling Services and fraud prevention.

3.3 To ensure that your credit, debit or charge card is not being used without your consent, we will validate name, address and other personal information supplied by you during the order process against appropriate third party databases. In performing these checks personal information provided by you may be disclosed to a registered Credit Reference Agency which may keep a record of that information. You can be rest assured that this is done only to confirm your identity, that a credit check is not performed and that your credit rating will be unaffected.

3.4 We will provide your first name, surname, invoice address, delivery address, company name, email address and telephone numbers to our courier or Royal Mail for the purposes of fulfilling the delivery of any Services you request. ?We may provide your order reference number, currency, total order price, order quantity and some aspects of the specification you have ordered such as the processor and graphics card to Google, Facebook, Bing and Hatch B.V. This is used for the purposes of sales tracking.

3.5 We will provide your email address, delivery country and any associated EAN numbers to Google Customer Reviews. Google Customer Reviews is a program that allows you to rate your purchase experience with partners who participate in the program. The rating that you give in your review can help other shoppers make an informed decision to purchase.

3.6 Information will not be provided to other third parties, other than agents of CCL Computers Ltd or where required by Law. We may disclose your information to agents for the purpose of processing and fulfilling your order. Such parties will include couriers, maintenance organisations, credit providers and others directly associated with the provision of the company’s products and services.

3.7 If you choose to use finance then we will provide your first name, surname, invoice address, delivery address, company name, email address, telephone numbers and IP address along to our finance provider. This information is used for the purpose of fulfilling our contract and fraud prevention. 

## 4.0 Data Protection and Security measures

We have taken every possible precaution to create a secure environment to protect the personal information supplied from you when making an order or opening an account. Access to your personal information is limited to people who need it to do their job. We may also contact you to verify and update data we hold on our records.

## 5 Cookies and Analytics

5.1 We use cookies for collecting user information from the Site. Cookies are used to enhance the user experience of the Site by remembering a specification previously configured, allowing the specification to be loaded easily when the Site is visited at a later date. Cookies are also used to track the effectiveness of marketing campaigns on external websites, by initially pointing the visitor to a tracking URL. Cookies are not used in any other way and we will never directly contact you based on data collected by cookies.

5.2 We use Google Analytics for the purposes of remarketing online. Third-party vendors, including Google, show our ads on websites across the Internet. The Site and third-party vendors, including Google, use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) together to inform, optimise, and serve ads based on your past visits to the Site. If you do not wish for your data to be collected and used by Google Analytics, you can opt-out.

## 6 Information Uses, Sharing & Disclosure

6.1 When you access or use the Services, we collect, use, share, and otherwise process your personal information as described in this policy. We rely on a number of legal bases to use your information in these ways. These legal bases include where:

You have consented to the processing, which you can revoke at any time; this includes marketing emails;

It is necessary to perform the contractual obligations in our Terms and Conditions and in order to provide a good service to you; these types of use are detailed above;

It is necessary to comply with a legal obligation, a court order, or to exercise or defend legal claims; for instance in case of fraud or claims;

It is necessary for the purposes of our or a third party’s legitimate interests, such as those of visitors or partners; for instance to improve and make the website and customer journey a better experience for our users, what people enjoy and how we can make it better. We may learn the sorts of products that you’re interested in from your browsing and purchasing behaviour on the website and suggest potential purchases as a result. We have a legitimate interest in customising your experience to help you discover relevant products. We may also needs to engage third-party companies and individuals (such as payment processors, research companies, and analytics and security providers) to help us operate, provide, and market our products. These third parties have only limited access to your information, may use your information only to perform these tasks on our behalf, and are obligated to not to disclose or use your information for other purposes.

We may share demographic information with business partners, but it will be aggregated and de-personalised, so that personal information is not revealed.

In the event CCL is involved in a business transaction (such as a sale, merger, liquidation, receivership, or transfer of all or substantially all of our assets), customer information is typically one of the business assets that is transferred. If we intend to transfer information about you, we will notify you by email and you will be given an opportunity to opt out before information about you becomes subject to a different privacy policy.

## 7.0 Your rights

You can request us to update, correct, or remove your personal data or ask us what information we hold by emailing dataprot@cclonline.com or by writing to us at the address below. However, please note that we may need to keep some personal data in order to process orders and to comply with customer service or after sale obligations.

We may send you emails about us or your activity. Some of these emails are required, service-related emails (such as customer support emails, order status emails or legal notices). Other emails are not required, such as newsletters. You will only receive marketing emails if you have consented and you can opt-out of newsletters by clicking the "unsubscribe" link at the bottom of the email.

You can contact us about privacy issues at privacy@cclonline.com or by post at Adrian Wood, Data Protection, CCL Computers Ltd, Inmoor Road, Cross Lane, Bradford. BD11 2PS
